ERIC DEBUSSCHERE

13344 Military Road SE · Rainier, WA 98576 · 360-506-9192 · eric.deb7@gmail.com

PROFILE

Hardworking mid-level generalist Software Engineer seeking employment after a two year sabbatical. Interested in learning new technologies and working on difficult technical problems. Seeking remote employment because my fiancée is immigrating to the US and we would like to remain location flexible until she finds US based employment.

EDUCATION

University of Arizona, Tucson, AZ Master of Science in Computer Science

2012

- GPA: 3.5
- Major Classes: Operating Systems, Networking, Graphics, Security, Design/Analysis of Algorithms, Bioinformatic Algorithms, Principles of Programming Languages, Project Management
- Completed a variety of projects in C, Java, and JavaScript (11,000+ lines of code)

University of Arizona, Eller College of Management, Tucson,

2012

AZ Master of Business Administration

- GMAT Score: 710. GPA: 3.4
- Focus: Finance, EntrepreneurshipIntel Case Competition Finalist

Undergraduate University of Texas - Dallas, Richardson, TX

2010

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

- Cum Laude Graduate 3.58 GPA
- Graduated in 3 years
- Third year took 8 Senior Level CS Classes, 39 Credits Total 3.84 GPA

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Professional Sabbatical / Traveled Extensively World Explorer

May 2019 - May 2021

- worth Employer
- Traveled to 15 countries in Europe
- Spent a month or more in China, Russia, Tibet, India, Egypt, Morocco
- Spent 4 months in England, 5 months in Denmark during the pandemic

Workiva Software Engineer

Dec 2012 - April 2019

- Utilized Java/Spring for backend, Dart (React) for frontend dev of new module for 2.0 version of Wdesk (1.5 years)
- Wrote server-side python (Django, App Engine, task queues, microservices) for Wdesk modules (3 years)
- Led refactoring effort on complex export feature processed through six backend microservices
- Assisted with transition from monolith to microservice based architecture. Used docker extensively.
- Wrote JavaScript (Angular) and native code for a dual-platform mobile app (using Cordova/PhoneGap) (1.5 years)

Intel

May 2011 - May 2012

Graduate Intern Technical (Software Engineer)

- Developed internal website software tools using ASP.net and JavaScript (Jquery)
- Led transition to object oriented JavaScript development and more sophisticated design patterns
- Wrote and optimized SQL queries for high performance and decreased latency

Hangchillparty.com

January - August 2010

Founder, sole developer

- Allows users to signal their social availability and "join up" with their friends.
- Syncs with Facebook and Twitter. Sends custom text messages to mobile devices.
- A rich web app developed with PHP, Object Oriented Javascript (Jquery Library), and MySQL.